## CONTACT



Phone

+447971088074



🖾 Email

Jamshed.habibi100@gmail.com



London, United Kingdom

## OTHER



Website

jamshedhabibi.com



In LinkedIn

linkedin.com/jamshed-habibi



Github

github.com/JamshedHabibi

## SKILLS

- **JavaScript**
- **TypeScript**
- React/Gatsby C
- HTML5
- CSS3 0
- Bootstrap
- CSS-in-JS 0
- React Semantic UI
- Lodash
- TDD (Jest) C
- **NGINX**
- Cloudflare 0
- Version Control (.Git)
- Continuous Integration (Netlify)

# INTERESTS

- Photography
- Travelling
- Fitness Enthusiast
- Chess

# Jamshed Habibi

#### SUMMARY

I've been building websites professionally for close to 2 years, specialising in front-end development and utilising technologies such as React, Gatsby, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS-in-JS, and many others. I have experience in test driven development, using Jest, and I am comfortable with Agile development practises, having received Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) Certification.

### **EDUCATION**

## University of Birmingham

September 2016 - July 2019

- BEng Mechanical Engineering Grade: First Class Honours
- Relevant Modules: Computing (84%), Mechatronics (71%), Control Engineering (75%)
- Mechanical Engineering Department Student Representative

#### Ark Putney Academy

September 2008 - June 2016

- A-Levels: Mathematics (A), Further Mathematics (B), Physics (B)
- GCSE's 11 A\*-C: Mathematics (A), Statistics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (B), Biology (B), English (B), Russian (B)
- Sixth Form Senior Prefect & Team Leader.
- Award received for exemplary contribution to mathematics department.

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

### Frontend Developer, David Lloyd Leisure

February 2020 - Present

- Worked in React to develop new web features, fix existing bugs, and maintain the website with up to 1 million visits per month, across 9 countries and 122 clubs.
- Led the development of the opening of new clubs in Switzerland, requiring new domain configurations and for DNS records to point to our servers to control the domain in Cloudflare. NGINX was also implemented to route existing pages to their relevant place on the new website.
- Led the front-end development on building a new customer referral scheme across the UK, allowing us to track referral conversions and issue gifts to successful referrals.
- Supported the migration of technologies, such as JavaScript to TypeScript and Tachyon to Emotion CSS-in-JS.
- Automated process of moving content across club files, using Bash scripting, making it much easier to restructure the CMS and speed up developer workflow, without errors.
- Took initiative to configure Netlify CMS to work locally, therefore developers can test tickets which involve the CMS, as they code and speed up developer testing.
- Implemented new civic cookie design changes, to drive as much analytics data as possible through to Google Analytics.

### Technology Systems Operator/Analyst, Hawk-Eye Innovations

June 2018 - October 2018

- Successfully operated goal line technology in 25+ football matches, earning the responsibility to manage a rig day by myself.
- Harvesting best practises from unrelated industries, I troubleshooted both hardware and software issues under immense time pressure, looking at the root of the problem and systematically eliminating potential causes. As a result, I prevented 100% of critical errors which allowed goal-line technology to operate effortlessly at crucial times.
- Routinely passed relentless UEFA accuracy checks for goal-line technology to 1mm accuracy, ensuring highly reliable delivery of the system, at the same time managing very high client expectation for repeat
- Provided additional analyst services to premier league teams, retrieving feeds from TV to put together a highlights package for teams to effectively review their players performance. Proving incredibly useful, we have negotiated new contracts with Manchester City and Southampton.
- One of few employees in the company building computational offside model points, using specialized software, which are flourishing in 100's of VAR-operated games.

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

# Client Blog Website (bambinakatarina.netlify.app)

July 2020 - August 2020

- Developed a blog website, using Gatsby/React, allowing for my client to seamlessly create content through Netlify CMS and automatically deploy to live using continuous integration.
- Written in TypeScript, instead of JavaScript to allow for increased code readability and early bug detection, with its rich IDE support.
- GraphQL was used to store blog content, as well as site data such as page SEO, permitting code to query data dynamically with reusable components.
- CSS-in-JS used to provide powerful style composition, with its ability to scope styles to specific components.

## Melbourne Tours (melbourne-tours.netlify.app)

January 2020

- Developed a web application, using React, providing available tours in the Melbourne, Australia.
- Used Google Firebase to implement user authentication, via logging in or signing up to the web app, allowing access to certain features, which would otherwise be blocked. Also implemented Firestore (NoSQL) to allow data storage, specific to user.
- React Semantic UI, in conjunction with JavaScript & CSS, was used to create a truly immersive UI/UX.